Isabella Karle and Jerome Karle Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Jerome Karle Papers, 1912-2009 (Box 174-412)
  - Subject File, 1912-2009 (Box 318-412)
    - Gavezzotti, Angelo; PROMET (computer program), 1998, mss85507_215_022
    - General Atomic and Molecular Electronic Structure System (GAMESS), 1998-1999, (2 folders) (Box 372)
    - Gilmont, Roger, 1961, 1992-1999, (5 folders) (Box 372)
    - Gilmont, Roger, 2000-2003, (2 folders) (Box 373)
    - Gindulyte, Asta, 1999-2005 (Box 373)
    - Glass model, undated (Box 373)
    - Gordon, Mark, 1999 (Box 373)
    - Gravity, 1913-1919, undated, (2 folders) (Box 373)
    - Grochowski, Jacek, 1993-1997 (Box 373)
    - Hafnium, 1999 (Box 373)
    - Hauptman, Herbert A., biographical information, circa 1985 (Box 373)
    - Heats of formation, 2002 (Box 373)
    - Heavy atom insertion, 1983-1984 (Box 373)
    - Helix, 1955, undated (Box 373)
    - Hendrickson, Wayne A., 1981-1990, (3 folders) (Box 374)
    - Hepatitis C, 1998 (Box 374)
    - High order determinants, 1970-1982, 1988-1994, undated, (3 folders) (Box 374)
    - High order invariants, undated (Box 374)
    - Hosemann, R., 1976-1978 (Box 374)
    - Hountas, Thanassis, 2001-2002 (Box 374)
    - "H. P. Roberson's Lectures on the Theory of Relativity," 1960 (Box 374)
    - Huang, Lulu (Box 374)
      - Correspondence, 1994, 2000, 2009 (Box 374)
      - Dissertation, 1993, (3 folders) (Box 375)
      - Geo-Centers, 1994-1998 (Box 375)
      - Job description, circa 1995 (Box 375)
      - Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 375)
      - Research items, 1994-1995 (Box 375)
    - Humor, 1997-2001 (Box 375)
    - Hypercube, 1995-1996 (Box 375)
    - Hyperdiagonals and dimensionality reduction, 1986-1987 (Box 375)
    - Inequalities, 1938, 1949-1975, (2 folders) (Box 375)
    - International Media Productions, 1990-1998 (Box 376)
    - International Science and Engineering Fair, Fort Worth, Tex., 1986, May 13-16 (Box 376)
    - Invariants and semivariants, slides, undated (Box 376)
    - Iodine, 1955, undated (Box 376)
    - Isomorphous substitution, undated (Box 376)
    - "Items relevant to symbolic addition revisited," 1999 (Box 376)
    - Japan, reprints and correspondence, 1951-1959 (Box 376)
    - Joint distribution, undated (Box 376)
    - Journal of the Brazilian Chemical Society, 1989-1993 (Box 376)
    - Journal of Heterocyclic Chemistry, 1990-1998 (Box 376)
    - Kitaĭgorodskiĭ, A. I. 1981 (Box 376)
    - Konnert, John, phase extension and refinement, 1996 (Box 376)
    - Koritsanszky, Tibor; XD (computer program), 1996-1999 (Box 376)
    - Laboratory notebook, 1944-1948 (Box 376)
    - Lang, Serge, 1989-2000, (6 folders) (Box 377)
    - Lang, Serge; Huntington, Samuel, 1987 (Box 377)
    - Lang, Serge; Huntington, Samuel, 1988-1990, (3 folders) (Box 378)
    - Least squares in anomalous dispersion, 1980-1982 (Box 378)
    - Leszczynski, Jerzy, 2002-2004 (Box 378)
    - Lin, Shu-Kun; Molecules (journal), 1997-2004 (Box 378)
    - Linear combinations, 1950-1956, undated (Box 378)
    - Linear programming, 1953-1962 (Box 378)
    - Linear programming, 1953-1966, 1980-1985, (2 folders) (Box 379)
    - "Liquid Structure Studies: Selection to the Discussion," Keszthely, Hungary, 1974, Aug. 27 (Box 379)
    - Löwdin, Per-Olov, 1997 (Box 379)
    - Low magnitudes, 1976-1985, (2 folders) (Box 379)
    - Magnitude formula for I₁ and I₀, 1973 (Box 379)
    - MacCHESS (computer program), 2002 (Box 379)
    - Maleic anhydride, 1962, 1977, 1995-1998, (2 folders) (Box 380)
    - Massa, Lou (Box 380)
      - Correspondence, 1987-2003, (6 folders) (Box 380)
      - Correspondence, 2004-2008 (Box 381)
      - Miscellany, 1991-2002, undated, (2 folders) (Box 381)
      - Quantum Crystallography (proposal), 1993 (Box 381)
      - "Quantum Crystallography: Density Matrix-Density Functional Theory and the X-Ray Diffraction Experiment" by Arnaud J. Soirat, 1990 (Box 381)
      - Science and Technology Resource Center for Quantum Crystallography (proposal), 1987 (Box 381)
      - Slater orbitals, 1970-1973, 1993 (Box 381)
      - Summer projects, 2000 (Box 381)
      - Superconductivity reprints, 1987-1988 (Box 381)
      - Uniqueness of density matrix from x-ray data, 1995 (Box 382)
      - United States Navy-American Society for Engineering Education summer faculty research program, 1987-1995, (2 folders) (Box 382)
      - Writings, 1985-2000, (3 folders) (Box 382)
    - Matrices and the phase problem, 1950-1998 (Box 382)
    - Matrices and space groups; Dispersion, K and L emission, 1930, 1949-1950 (Box 382)
    - Methane hydrates, 1951, 1965-1977, 1996-2001 (Box 382)
    - Mezey, Paul, 1990-2002, (5 folders) (Box 383)
    - Mezey, Paul; Macromolecules, 2002 (Box 383)
    - Michelson, Albert A., 1967-1973 (Box 383)
    - Microphotometer, undated (Box 383)
    - Microscope, 1969-1976 (Box 383)
    - Mid-Atlantic Protein Crystallography Workshop, Rockville, Md., 1991, May 16-18 (Box 383)
    - Models for N₃⁻ and N₅⁺, 1999 (Box 384)
    - Mohave toxin, 1988 (Box 384)
    - MOPAC2002 (computer program), 2002 (Box 384)
    - "More than one type of anomalous scatterer," 1984-1989 (Box 384)
    - Morino, Yonezo, 1997 (Box 384)
    - Mouvement Universel de la Responsabilité Scientifique, 1986-1988 (Box 384)
    - N₂, 1974, 1993, 2000 (Box 384)
    - N₄T calculations, 1998 (Box 384)
    - N₈ calculations, circa 1990s (Box 384)
    - National Register of Scientific and Technical Personnel, 1956-1970 (Box 384)
    - NATO Advanced Study Institute, 1980 (Box 384)
    - NATO Advanced Study Institute, "Direct Methods in Crystallography," Italy, 1974, Mar. 25-Apr. 6 (Box 384)
    - "The Natural Step USA," 1996 (Box 384)
    - NF₂ groups, 1993, 1999-2000 (Box 384)
    - Neutron diffraction, undated (Box 384)
    - Neutrons, undated (Box 384)
    - Note card file, undated See Container OV 1, same heading (Box OV 1)
    - Notes (Box 384)
      - Euler angles, undated (Box 384)
      - Miscellany, 1930-1947, 1971-2005, undated, (8 folders) (Box 385)
      - Miscellany, undated, (5 folders) (Box 386)
      - Test calculations, 1980-1983 (Box 386)
    - "NW Chem User Documentation," 1998-1999 (Box 386)
    - Nylon pentane prolines, undated (Box 386)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tenn., 1977 (Box 386)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tenn., 1981 (Box 387)
    - Octanitrocubane, 2000 (Box 387)
    - Office of Technology Assessment, U.S. Congress, 1978-1982 See also Container 387, same heading (Box 387)
    - P₄, circa 1995 (Box 387)
    - Parametrizing space, 1975-1984 (Box 387)
    - Parr, Robert G., 1992 (Box 387)
    - Pett, Virginia, 2000-2002 (Box 387)
    - Phase and coordinate determination, 1989-2000, (3 folders) (Box 387)
    - Phase formulas, 1993-1994 (Box 387)
    - Phases from zero atoms in a unit cell, 2004 (Box 387)
    - "Pinkerton's compound," 1994-1995 (Box 388)
    - Pittsburgh Diffraction Conference, Valley Forge, Pa., 1993, Nov. 3-5 (Box 388)
    - Planck-Benzinger thermal work function, 1987 (Box 388)
    - P matrix, 1970, 1989-1994, (3 folders) (Box 388)
    - Polymers, 1980 (Box 388)
    - Polypeptides, 2000 (Box 388)
    - Pople, John, 1996-2004 (Box 388)
    - Probability distribution at coordinates, 1952, undated (Box 389)
    - Protein Data Bank (newsletter), 1987-1999, (2 folders) (Box 389)
    - "Quantum Chemistry Symposium on Current Aspects of Open-Shell Calculations," Frederick, Md., 1997, June 17 (Box 389)
    - Quantum Crystallography (Box 389)
      - Calculations, 1994-1995 (Box 389)
      - Chronological file, 1988 (Box 389)
      - Chronological file, 1989-1990, (2 folders) (Box 390)
      - Illustrations, 1994 (Box 390)
      - Miscellany, 1967, 1982-1992, (3 folders) (Box 390)
      - Miscellany, 1989-2000 See also Container OV 4, same heading, (7 folders) (Box 391)
      - Notes, 1990-1994, (2 folders) (Box 391)
      - "Possible problem," 1990-1994 (Box 391)
      - Tests, 1991-1994 (Box 392)
    - Randic, Milan, 1976, 1990-1991, 2002, (2 folders) (Box 392)
    - Randic, Milan; Mathematical chemistry series, 1991-1992 (Box 392)
    - Random and alternating least squares, 1991-1992 (Box 392)
    - Rearrangements, slides, 1968, undated (Box 392)
    - Recommendations and Nominations (Box 392)
      - Allinger, Norman, 1994, 2001 (Box 392)
      - Bartell, Lawrence, 1989-1992, 1999 (Box 392)
      - Bartlett, Rodney, 2001-2003 (Box 392)
      - B-C, 1986-1993, 2003 (Box 392)
      - Chidambaram, R., 1993-1995 (Box 392)
      - Coffey, Timothy, 1989-1991 (Box 392)
      - Coppens, Philip, 1993 (Box 392)
      - Cowley, J. M., 1982-1987 (Box 392)
      - Drickhamer, Harry G., 1999-2000 (Box 392)
      - D-F, 1987-1990, 1997-1999 (Box 392)
      - Gindulyte, Asta, 1999-2001 (Box 392)
      - Goodenough, John B., 2003-2005 (Box 392)
      - Hauptman, Herbert A., 1977-1978, 1985-1987 (Box 393)
      - G-H, 1984-1994 (Box 393)
      - Hendrickson, Wayne A., 1980-1984, 1995-1998 (Box 393)
      - H-L, 1976-1978, 1987-1998 (Box 393)
      - Massa, Lou, 1995-2007 (Box 393)
      - M-P, 1986-2002 (Box 393)
      - Randic, Milan, 2002 (Box 393)
      - Rath, B. B., 1990-1994, 2002 (Box 393)
      - Rossman, Michael, 1989-1997 (Box 393)
      - Smith, Janet, 1989-2004 (Box 393)
      - S-W, 1983-2000 (Box 393)
      - Witkop, Bernhard, 1978-1986, (3 folders) (Box 394)
      - Zuk, William, 2001-2004 (Box 394)
    - Referee comments by Karle (Box 394)
      - Acta Crystallographica, 1984-1998, (4 folders) (Box 394)
      - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1984, 2001 (Box 395)
      - Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences, 2002 (Box 395)
      - Journal of Physical Chemistry, 1999-2002, (2 folders) (Box 395)
      - Miscellaneous journals, 1972, 1986-1998, 2004, (2 folders) (Box 395)
      - National Science Foundation, 1982-1991 (Box 395)
      - Petroleum Research Fund, 1995-1997 (Box 395)
      - Proceedings of the Tenth International Symposium on Organic Crystal Chemistry, 1997 (Box 395)
      - Proteins (journal), 1992, 2000 (Box 395)
      - United States-Israel Binational Science Foundation, 1984-1987 (Box 395)
    - "Relativistic Quantum Mechanics and Quantum Field Theory," lectures by J. Sucher, undated (Box 396)
    - Relativity (Box 396)
      - Earth satellites, 1958 (Box 396)
      - Experimental verification, circa 1957 (Box 396)
      - Reprints, 1912-1919, 1940 (Box 396)
    - "Report on Electron Diffraction Investigation" by L. O. Brockway and R. L. Livingston, 1944, June 30, 1954-1959, (2 folders) (Box 396)
    - Reprints, miscellaneous, 1934, 1950, 1962-1979, (2 folders) (Box 396)
    - Reprints, miscellaneous, 1981-2008, undated, (4 folders) (Box 397)
    - Research file, circa 1948-circa 1964 (Box 397)
    - Research file, circa 1948-circa 1964, (4 folders) (Box 398)
    - Research file, circa 1948-circa 1964, (3 folders) (Box 399)
    - Research file, circa 1948-circa 1964, (4 folders) (Box 400)
    - Research file, circa 1948-circa 1964, (3 folders) (Box 401)
    - Research file, circa 1948-circa 1964, (4 folders) (Box 402)
    - Research file, circa 1948-circa 1964, (9 folders) (Box 403)
    - "Restoring Scientific Integrity in Policy Making," Union of Concerned Scientists, 2004 (Box 404)
    - "Restrained Parameter Anisotropic Thermal Factor Refinement Procedure," 1976-1981 (Box 404)
    - Ribosome, 2002-2003, (2 folders) (Box 404)
    - Rietveld program, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Ga., 1988 (Box 404)
    - Rolling successes, 1990 (Box 404)
    - Rossman, Michael, 1973-1974 (Box 404)
    - Sahni, Viraht, 2000 (Box 404)
    - Scanning tunneling microscopy, 1982-1990 (Box 404)
    - Schulten, K.; Photosynthesis, 1995-1997 (Box 404)
    - Science funding, 1992-2000 (Box 404)
    - "Science and Technology Message of the President," 1979 (Box 404)
    - Secondhand smoke, 1979-1980, (2 folders) (Box 405)
    - Seeing orbitals, 1999 (Box 405)
    - Single exact algebra, 1984 (Box 405)
    - "Sir Walter Raleigh method," 1985 (Box 405)
    - Slater, John C., 1999 (Box 405)
    - Slides, miscellaneous, 1965-1988, undated See also Container OV 2, same heading, (5 folders) (Box 405)
    - Slides, miscellaneous, undated, (2 folders) (Box 406)
    - Smithsonian Institution, 1993 (Box 406)
    - Space Station Freedom Program, 1992 (Box 406)
    - Spallation Neutron Source, Oak Ridge National Laboratory; Los Alamos National Laboratory, 1983, 2000 (Box 406)
    - Sparks, Robert A., International Business Machines Corp., 1960-1962 (Box 406)
    - Special calculations for energetic materials, 1989-1998, (2 folders) (Box 406)
    - Spheroidal coordinates, 1951, 1965-1969, undated (Box 406)
    - Spurrite, undated (Box 406)
    - Stanford Synchrotron Radiation Laboratory, Menlo Park, Calif., 1976-2004 (Box 406)
    - Stanford Synchrotron Radiation Laboratory, Menlo Park, Calif., 1976-2004, (2 folders) (Box 407)
    - Static Synergetics Research, undated (Box 407)
    - Steroids, slides, undated (Box 407)
    - Stouch, Terry, 1994-1997 (Box 407)
    - Structural Chemistry (publication), 1988-1992 (Box 407)
    - Structure and reactivity, 1967-1986 (Box 407)
    - "Study of Hazardous Substances and Procedures in the Laboratory," 1976-1978 (Box 407)
    - Superconductivity, 1955, 1963-1968, 1983-1993, (5 folders) (Box 407)
    - Superconductivity, 1987-1993 (Box 408)
    - Symmetry (publication), 1988-1994 (Box 408)
    - Symmetry-Adapted Perturbation Theory (SAPT), 2000, (3 folders) (Box 408)
    - Sympozjum Krystalochemii Organicznej, Dymaczewo K. Poznania, Poland, 1977, Sept. (Box 408)
    - Synchrotron, 1976-1989, 2001 (Box 408)
    - "Systematic Investigations into Electrostatic Immersion Objectives" by E. A. Soa, 1959, 1965 (Box 408)
    - Tables of invariants, undated (Box 408)
    - Tangent formula; notes, 1991-1994 (Box 408)
    - "Tangent Formula Program for the X-Ray Analysis of Noncentrosymmetric Crystals," 1968 (Box 409)
    - Taxol, 1991 (Box 409)
    - Tetrazines, 1998 (Box 409)
    - Theoretical chemistry, 1975-1980, (3 folders) (Box 409)
    - Thymine, slides, undated (Box 409)
    - TiO₂ semiconductor, 1969-1974 (Box 409)
    - Toth, Lou, 1987 (Box 409)
    - Translation function, 1972, 1985 (Box 409)
    - Trichothecenes, 1986 (Box 409)
    - "Trilinear Chart of Nuclides," William H. Sullivan, 1957 (Box 409)
    - Tryptorphan transfer RNA synthestase; Cardter, Charles and David Coleman, 1988-1989 (Box 409)
    - Tsoucaris, Georges, 1969, 1979, 1988-1992 (Box 410)
    - Ultimate fast fourier, 2002-2003 (Box 410)
    - "Unusual requests," 1991-1993 (Box 410)
    - United States Arms and Disarmament Agency, 1979-1984, (5 folders) (Box 410)
    - United States Arms and Disarmament Agency, 1985-1986 (Box 411)
    - United States president's message on science and technology, 1972 (Box 411)
    - Vacuum half-box electrometer, 1949-1950, 1959 See also Container OV 3, same heading (Box 411)
    - "Various reading topics," 1987, 2002, undated (Box 411)
    - Weissenberg automatic data collection, undated (Box 411)
    - Williams, Don, 1973, 1999 (Box 411)
    - Witkop, Bernhard, 1968-1996, undated, (3 folders) (Box 411)
    - X-ray surface scattering, 1983 (Box 412)
    - Yamaguchi, Kaoru; World futures-creating seminars, 1993-1995 (Box 412)
    - Yang, Weitao, 1992-2000 (Box 412)
    - Σ₃ for P2₁, undated (Box 412)
    - Σ₃ for P2₁/m, undated (Box 412)
    - Σ₃ for P2₁P2₁P2₁, undated (Box 412)
- Collaborations, 1920-2009 (Box 412-429)
  The Collaborations series contains materials related to projects, writings, speeches, and presentations on which Isabella and Jerome participated together, the bulk of which span from 1950 to 2009. The series contains many files related to their involvement as instructors with the International School of Crystallography and NATO Advanced Study Institute from the 1960s through the 1980s. Biographical materials that provide insight into their working relationship include oral history interview transcripts, clippings, and interviews. Other notable topics and material types include C₂Cl₆ research, travel engagements, retirement information, correspondence, and awards.
  Material types include awards, transcripts, clippings, photographs, correspondence, articles, presentations, speeches, lectures, notes, and schedules.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject or material type.
  - Awards, 1970, 1981-1986, 2001-2002 (Box 412)
  - Biographical file, 1978, 1986, undated (Box 412)
  - C₂Cl₆, 1952-1955, (4 folders) (Box 412)
  - C₂Cl₆, 1952-1955, (2 folders) (Box 413)
  - Clippings featuring Isabella and Jerome, 1967-1998 (Box 413)
  - Correspondence, 1950-2009, (3 folders) (Box 413)
  - Crystallographic Compuing School, Bischenberg, France, 1990, July 29-Aug. 5 (Box 413)
  - Congreso y Exposición de la Industria Química, Caracas, Venezuela, 1991, July (Box 413)
  - Escola Latinoamericana de Cristalografia: Métodos Diretos, São Paulo, Brazil, 1976, July 19-30, (3 folders) (Box 413)
  - Escola Latinoamericana de Cristalografia: Métodos Diretos, São Paulo, Brazil, 1976, July 19-30, (2 folders) (Box 414)
  - Ethiopian Orphan Foundation; Abebe, Moges, 1988-1995 (Box 414)
  - First Naples Workshop on Bioactive Peptides, Capri, Italy, 1988, May 24-26 (Box 414)
  - Hanson, Louise, 1988-1997 (Box 414)
  - International School of Crystallography: Direct Methods of Solving Crystal Structures, Sicily, Italy, 1978, Mar. 27-Apr. 9 (Box 414)
  - International School of Crystallography: Direct Methods of Solving Crystal Structures, Sicily, Italy, 1978, Mar. 27-Apr. 9, (2 folders) (Box 415)
  - International School of Crystallography: Direct Methods of Solving Crystal Structures, Sicily, Italy, 1984, Apr. 7-19, (3 folders) (Box 415)
  - International Science and Engineering Fair, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1987, May 12-15 (Box 415)
  - International Summer School on Crystallographic Computing, Ottawa, Canada, 1969, Aug. 4-12 (Box 416)
  - International Summer School on Crystallographic Computing, Prague, Czech Republic, 1975, July 28-Aug. 5 See also Container 28, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 416)
  - Interview with Brian VanDeMark, 1998 (Box 416)
  - Isabella and Jerome Karle Award, City University of New York, City College, 1986-2004, (2 folders) (Box 416)
  - Materials for 2008 Naval Research Laboratory display, 2005-2008, undated (Box 416)
  - NATO Advanced Study Institute on Chemical Crystallography with Pulsed Neutrons and Synchrotron X-Rays, Lisbon, Portugal, 1987, Mar. 17-27 (Box 416)
  - NATO Advanced Study Institute on Direct Methods in Crystallography, York, England, 1980, Aug. 4-15 See also Container 29, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 417)
  - NATO Advanced Study Institute on Direct and Patterson Methods of Solving Crystal Structures, Parma, Italy, 1970, Sept. 7-19 See also Container 29, same heading, (4 folders) (Box 417)
  - NATO Advanced Study Institute on Direct and Patterson Methods of Solving Crystal Structures, York, England, 1971, Sept. 6-17, (2 folders) (Box 418)
  - Navy League of the United States, 1987 (Box 418)
  - Oral history interviews, 1987, 2007, (3 folders) (Box 418)
  - Photographs, circa 1920-1949, 2000, undated (Box 418)
  - Photographs, 1987, undated (Box 419)
  - Renaissance Institute, 2008 (Box 419)
  - Reprint requests, 1950-1981, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 419)
  - "Research activities, biographical data, and publication lists", 1980 (Box 419)
  - Retirement, 2009 (Box 419)
  - School on Direct Methods and Macromolecular Crystallography, Buffalo, N.Y., 1983, July 20-29, (2 folders) (Box 419)
  - Shivanandan, Kandiah, 2007-2008 (Box 419)
  - Sixth Polish School of Crystallography, Kielce, Poland, 1979, Sept. 3-14 (Box 419)
  - "Social Context of Extraordinary Individuals" by Carol A. Mockros, 1996 (Box 419)
  - Speeches, 1960 (Box 419)
  - Speeches, 1962-1971, (5 folders) (Box 420)
  - Speeches, 1972-1979, (6 folders) (Box 421)
  - Speeches, 1979-1990, (9 folders) (Box 422)
  - Speeches, 1992-2001, (7 folders) (Box 423)
  - Summer School in Modern Methods of Crystal Structure Development, Manchester, England, 1960, Aug. 29-Sept. 9 See also Container OV 3, same heading (Box 423)
  - Summer School on X-Ray Crystal Structure Analysis, Jabłonna, Poland, 1974, June 3-15 (Box 423)
  - Travel, 1959-1960, 1968-1977, 1989-1992, (6 folders) (Box 424)
  - Tsoucaris, Georges, 2000 (Box 424)
  - Union of Concerned Scientists, 1990-2003 (Box 424)
  - United States Naval Academy, 1999 (Box 424)
  - University of Michigan, 1986-2005 (Box 424)
  - "Views on Science Policy of the Nobel Laureates for 1985," hearing before the Committee on Science and Technology, U.S. House of Representatives, 1986, May 21 (Box 424)
  - World Federation of Scientists, 1995-2003 (Box 424)
  - Writings, 1947-1973, (9 folders) (Box 425)
  - Writings, 1973, (4 folders) (Box 426)
  - Writings, 1973-1983, (9 folders) (Box 427)
  - Writings, 1985-1989, 1999, (8 folders) (Box 428)
  - Writings, 1999-2009, undated, (6 folders) (Box 429)
- Oversize, 1958-2000 (Box OV 1-OV 65)
  Material types include crystallographic data printouts, figures, illustrations, posters, note cards, glass slides, and blueprints.
  Listed and described according to the series, subseries, containers, and folders from which the items were separated.
  - Isabella Karle Papers
    - Speeches and Writings
      - Speeches, glass plates, circa 1965-circa 1975 (Container 31, same heading) (Box OV 2)
    - Subject File
      - Frogs, glass plates, undated (Container 43, same heading) (Box OV 2)
    - Research File
      - URRY2, illustration, circa 1983 (Container 72, same heading) (Box OV 4)
      - GRAMI A
        - Crystallographic data printouts, 1973-1974, 1980-1983 (Box OV 5-OV 7)
        - Crystallographic data printouts, circa 1973-circa 1999 (Container 75, same heading) (Box OV 65)
        - Figures and illustrations, circa 1973-1980s (Container 75, same heading) (Box OV 65)
      - Antamanide, crystallographic data printouts, 1972-1973 (Box OV 8-OV 10)
      - Antamanide (NaBr), crystallographic data printouts, 1972-1973 (Box OV 11-OV 14)
      - Antamanide (Phe⁴Val⁶), 1977 (Container 78, same heading) (Box OV 15-OV 16)
      - Antamanide (Phe⁴Val⁶)
        - Figures and illustrations, 1974-1976 (Container 79, same heading) (Box OV 20)
        - Crystallographic data printouts, 1974-1976 (Container 79, same heading) (Box OV 20)
        - Crystallographic data printouts, 1975-1976 (Box OV 17-OV 19)
      - Tetrapeptide, Cedric H. Hassall, crystallographic data printouts, 1970-1974 (Container 80, same heading) (Box OV 21-OV 22)
      - Hassall, Cedric H., research data and correspondence
        - Figures and illustrations, undated (Container 80, same heading) (Box OV 4)
        - Crystallographic data printouts, 1971-1973, undated (Container 80, same heading) (Box OV 23)
        - Crystallographic data printouts, circa 1965-circa 1973 (Container 80, same heading) (Box OV 63)
      - Jamine OPII, data and correspondence, crystallographic data printouts, 1963 (Container 80, same heading) (Box OV 23-OV 25)
      - Arginine, data, figures and illustrations, circa 1958-circa 1963 (Container 81, same heading) (Box OV 4)
      - Arginine, crystallographic data printouts, graph, k-points, circa 1958-circa 1963 (Container 82, same heading) (Box OV 3)
      - Reserpine, crystallographic data printouts, 1964-1967 (Box OV 30-OV 32)
      - Reserpine, data and abstract, crystallographic data printouts, 1959, 1967 (Container 83, same heading) (Box OV 30)
      - Hexaglycyl, crystallographic data printouts, circa 1961-1966, 1973, 1973 (Box OV 33-OV 35)
      - Cyclic GLY PRO GLY, data, images, and manuscript
        - Figures and illustrations, 1976-1977 (Container 84, same heading) (Box OV 35)
        - Illustration, circa 1976 (Container 84, same heading) (Box OV 4)
      - Cyclic GLY PRO GLY, crystallographic data printouts, 1976-1977 (Box OV 35-OV 36)